So in the last section we significantly increased the speed by which our neural
上一节课 我们大幅提高了
network.
神经网络的训练速度
Even in the last section,
甚至在上一节课
seeing something in the realm of 1,500 reviews per second in our test data.
我们看到了测试数据每秒处理 1,500 个左右的评论
I mean, just absolutely screaming.
简直高得吓人
Now, in this section we're going to go back one chapter and
这一节课 我们将倒回一个章节
continue to try to reduce the amount of
继续尝试减少网络训练中的噪音量
noise that our network has to go through and increase the amount of signal.
并且增加信号量
This signal to noise ratio, the more that you can do
也就是信噪比 你越能帮助
to help the neural network cut though the really obvious steps but
神经网络快速完成简单明了的步骤
it can then focus on the really difficult stuff,
它就越能聚焦在处理那些真正有难度的步骤上
the better your neural network will be able to train.
你的神经网络也就能训练得越好
And that's really what we want to continue to iterate.
这就是我们真正想要继续迭代的
So once again it's about framing of the problem so
因此 当我们开始构建解决问题的框架
the neural net can be as successful as possible.
使神经网络变得尽可能成功
As we've already seen a few relatively small changes can have
我们已经看到 一些细小的改动
a drastic impact on how fast the network trains,
会大幅影响网络的训练速度
how much it's able to identify the underlying pattern that you care about.
以及网络能在多大程度上识别你真正关心的底层模式
And we're just going to continue to iterate.
我们将继续迭代
So in this section we're going to go back to it and
所以在这一小节 我们将回过头来
say, okay what is our neural network doing.
问问“我们的神经网络到底在做什么？”
This is the question that we're always asking.
这是我们一直在问的一个问题
What is really happening under the hood.
它的背后究竟在发生什么？
So this is, right now we're adding these vectors together that's repeated in
现在 我们将这些向量加到一块
this vector, and that's making a prediction.
来进行预测
So this ends up being a sum of all of the words that exist in the in review.
最后 这就是每个单词在评论中出现次数的总和
Now it's funny.
有一点很有意思
Earlier when we were doing a small little validation of our
之前 在对我们的想法进行一个小小的
[LAUGH] of our idea.
验证时
What did we do.
我们做了什么呢
We created this ratio where
我们创建了这个比率
we identified what words were really important.
来发现那些真正重要的单词
What words had the highest correlation, flawless, superbly,
相关性最高的词 比如 flawless、superbly
perfection, or unwatchable, pointless, atrocious, redeeming, laughable.
perfection 或 unwatchable、pointless、atrocious、redeeming、laughable
And it got me wondering.
这不禁使我在想
Well what if we use these
如果我们用这些信息
to help continue to weight it more in favor where it's like, hey, neural net.
有倾向性地赋予一些词权重 是否更好？
Look here.
就像对神经网络说 看这里
It's okay if you look at other places too, I suppose.
你要在其他地方找也没关系
But start with this at least at a very minimum.
但最好先从这些词开始
Or if we just actually said, hey, this is where the gold is.
或者我们直接说“金子就在这里”
Start digging.
开始挖吧
Not everyone of these words bowl and you and seagull or
不是每个词都那么重要 比如像 Boll uwe Seagal
Segal, I guess it's, that's not too bad.
'Seagal' 这个词太糟了
Seagull is one of the worst.
'Seagal' 是最糟的词之一
[INAUDIBLE] corded terms and don't tell them.
最负面相关的词之一 不要告诉他哦（注：Seagal是一位美国好莱坞动作明星）
So here like Gandhi.
像这里的 Gandhi
That's probably just a movie about Gandhi.
这可能只是一部关于甘地的电影
I know that it really tells you much about the sentiment.
我觉得这好像跟情绪没多大关系
So flawless, superbly, perfection,
而 flawless、superbly、perfection
these are the ones we want the neural net to find.
这些才是我们希望神经网络找到的词
But if you're thinking this is you're digging for gold.
你可以想象成你在挖金子
This is a really gold rich section.
这些词就在金子的富矿区
There's still some rock and some iron and stuff in here.
虽然也有一些石头和铁和其他东西
But I mean, this stuff right here.
但是 这些词就是我们的目标
This is what we want our neuronet to be naturally finding.
是我们希望神经网络能自然找到的词
So how can we actually use this statistic to help adia.
那么 我们如何利用这些统计数据来帮助我们做预测呢？
I mean would that even make sense to do.
它能帮你做些什么？
Well, what if we did a cut off.
比如 我们先将一些词去掉
Would that, we're going to actually limit the vocabulary.
它会起作用吗？ 我们将限制词汇量的规模
Well, to investigate that,
首先 我们来研究一下
we actually want to see what the distribution is on this ratio.
看看这些单词比率值的分布情况是怎么样的
Now for that, visualization libraries are great.
为此 可视化库能派上大用场
Check this out.
看这里
This is our ratio.
这是我们的比率
Zero was totally neutral, and
0 处在正中间的位置
the frequency kind of this distribution.
频率的分布是这样的
So it's normalized.
因此 这个分布是归一化的
But there's a ton of words that are kind of ambiguous.
但是 有一大堆词是模棱两可的
Not really positive and not really negative.
它们既不是非常正面的 也不是非常负面的
They're kind of in the middle.
而是大概处于中间位置
And then over here is actually a relatively small number that are just
而在两边 这些实际上非常少量的词
real punchers, the ones that really, really matter.
才是真正的重点 这些词非常非常重要
And to me, this is great because If these ones don't really matter,
对于我来说这样很好 因为如果这些词不重要
if this is the a, b, periods, commas of the world and
如果它们只是 a、b、句号、逗号之类的
they happen all the time then I can get rid of these.
出现的频率非常高 那么我可以剔除它们
And it's going to save me tons of computational time, because because
这会为我节省大量的计算时间 因为
these are really frequent, but it shouldn't effect quality negatively.
它们确实出现得很频繁 而且剔除它们并不会影响最终的表现质量
In fact, if anything it should effect quality positively because they
事实上 反而会有积极的影响 因为
don't have that much predictive power.
这些常见词并不具有很强的预测力
So we have a ton on words in our corpus that don't have predictive power.
我们的语料库中有大量不具有预测力的单词
So let's get rid of them.
那么 我们就剔除掉它们吧
That's just going to make our neural net that much stronger.
这只会让我们的神经网络更加强大
Now before we quite jump there let's look at one more distribution.
在我们开始动手之前 再来看一个分布
This is the relative frequency of different terms.
这是不同单词的相对出现频率
It's called a Zitvian distribution normally.
通常称为 Zitvian 分布
Our corpus is so extreme that there are a few terms that dominate.
我们的语料库非常极端化 有几个词明显处于主导地位
I mean like these few words are just way more frequent than all the rest.
也就是说 有几个词的出现频率比其他的词要高得多
Now look at that.
看看这里
And to me this is interesting.
对我来说 这非常有意思
And actually in natural processing it comes common trend is to eliminate
实际上在自然语言处理中 一个普遍的趋势就是
the stuff that's both most frequent and the stuff that's most infrequent.
剔除最高频和最低频的词
The stuff that almost never happens.
像这里这些几乎永远不会出现的词
Why.
为什么？
Stuff that's really frequent, like the, a, and.
频率非常高的那些词 像 the、a、and
It happens so much that it doesn't really give you much signal.
它们出现得太频繁了 无法给你什么信息
So if it's really infrequent, if it only happens once, that's not a pattern.
而那些最不频繁的呢 它只发生一次 没形成一种模式
That's just it happening once.
如果只发生一次的话
How can you say that's correlation when if you only see it one time.
你怎么能说它一定存在某种相关性呢？
So people tend to kind of trim from both sides in actually approximating when
所以在自然语言处理中 当人们做一个有意思的分类器时
they're trying to make a class fire that does something really interesting.
人们都倾向于将出现频率过多和过少的词都剔除掉 再进行分类
So what we're really doing is we're looking at these kind of broad
所以 我们真正在做的 是观察这些概括性的
visualizations and say hey, what is signal and what is noise.
可视化图像 找出信号是什么 噪音是什么
And can we use these different metrics to cut out noise and add in signal.
看看我们能否使用这些不同的指标 消除噪音 增强信号
So in here, I'm looking at this and I'm going big chunk of noise right here.
所以在这里 我看到有一大片噪音
Extremely frequent and not very useful.
它们非常频繁 但又无用
I'm going to cut this out.
我要将它们去除掉
And I'm looking here, and I'm going, hmm, yeah.
然后看看这里
There's a lot of stuff in here too.
这里也有很多东西要处理
Now, I think these are actually, this big part is going to be in here.
我觉得这些 这一大块对应的是这里
This is actually a better filter for getting out the really frequent stuff.
这个过滤器能更好地将高频词清除出去
But as far as this stuff, you can't even see it because it's so infrequent.
而这里的这些词 你甚至看不到它们 因为它们的出现频率实在太低了
I think we're going to try to carve that out too.
我们也要将这部分剔除掉
So Project six.
这就到项目 6 了
Project six I'm really excited about.
我真的很激动
This one's great.
项目 6 是一个很棒的项目
Project six is going to be about making learning faster by reducing noise
项目 6 的目标是通过使用这些统计数据 这些思路降低噪音
using these statistics, these ideas.
从而提高学习速度
There's no general neural net rule that says that this is how you do it.
并没有什么通用的神经网络规则规定你要这么做
What we're doing is we're framing the problem to
我们要做的是搭建处理这个问题的框架
make the correlation as obvious as possible to the neural net so
使相关性对于神经网络来说尽可能明显
that it has the best chance to ignore noise and to find signal.
让它更容易忽略噪音并找到信号
That's what framing the problem is all about.
这就是解决问题的核心所在
So in the next project, what we're going to do is we're going to
所以在下一个项目中 我们要做的就是
install these metrics into our neural net.
将这些指标添加到我们的神经网络中
I want you to go ahead and give it a shot.
我想让你来试一试 00:06:34,230 --&gt; 00:06:38,161 看看能不能构建这个神经网络 或修改这个网络
so that in the train method or the sediment network method,
在训练方法或 SentimentNetwork 方法中
you put in a parameter that says, how much of this to carve out.
放入一个参数 表示你将剔除多少比例的词汇
You put in a parameter that says, hey,
放入一些个参数 表示
get rid of all the words that are too frequent or infrequent.
要清除频率最高和频率最低的那些词
And you'll have a min count.
你会设置最低计数
Each word has to show up at least ten times, at least five times to be
比如说 每个词至少要出现 10 次 或者 5 次
included in my vocabulary and to be included in my neural net.
这些词才能进入到神经网络中
And see how that goes.
然后看看效果如何
So take a crack at that.
那么 让我们来试试吧
In a minute we'll pull up one that works and talk about it.
一会儿 我将挑出一个可以成功运作的网络来聊一聊
I'll see you there.
到时候见